Interfaces can be thought of as a
インターフェイスとは
contract on functionality.
機能の契約だとも考えられます
Any class that implements an interface
インターフェイスを実装するクラスは
must have all of it's methods and properties.
すべてのメソッドとプロパティを保持する必要があります
In exchange the implementing class
その代わりに実装するクラスはポリモーフィズム（多態性）を使用し
can be treated like the interface by other classes
他のクラスからインターフェイスのように
using polymorphism.
扱われるようになります
It is important to note that interfaces are
なおインターフェイスはクラスではなく
not classes and cannot have their own instances.
自らのインスタンスを持てない点に注意してください
While inheritance is an Is A relationship
以前取り上げたとおり継承は is-a 関係で表されます
where one class inherits from another
ひとつのクラスが別のクラスから継承するという関係ですね
interfaces use an Implements relationship.
インターフェイスでは Implements （実装）関係で表されます
Where one class implements an interface.
ひとつのクラスがインターフェイスを実装するわけです
Interfaces are usually declared outside of a class.
インターフェイスは通常クラスの外側で宣言されます
When declaring interfaces you would
インターフェイスを宣言する場合には通常
commonly use one script per interface,
インターフェイスごとにスクリプトを作ります
but for the purpose of this example we're going
ただしこの例では同一スクリプトに 2 つのインターフェイスを
to show two in the same script.
宣言してみます
By convention interfaces are declared
インターフェイス名を宣言するときは
using a name that starts with a capital I
通則的に大文字の I からはじめます
followed by a name that starts with another capital letter.
そしてその次の文字も大文字とします
Since interfaces normally describe some functionality
インターフェイスは通常何らかの機能を記述するものなので
that the implementing classes will have
実装クラス内には接尾詞「able」（できる）がついた
a lot of interfaces end in the postfix 'able'.
インターフェイスが多数存在することが多いです
It is worth noting however that this is not
なおこれは必須ではありませんし
mandatory and could potentially be
その用途によっては混乱を招く可能性もあるので
misleading depending on the interface.
気をつけてください
We have declared two interfaces here,
さてこれで 2 つのインターフェイスを宣言できました
IKillable and IDamageable.
IKillable と IDamageable です
In IKillable we have a function called Kill,
IKillable には Kill という関数があります
which has a return type of void and no parameters.
この関数の戻り値の型は void でパラメーターも取りません
Any class which implements the IKillable interface
この IKillable インターフェイスを実装するクラスは
must have a public function which matches this signature.
この署名に合う public な関数を持つ必要があります
The IDamageable interface has a generic type T.
IDamageable インターフェイスは generic 型の T を持ちます
This means that anything in the interface
これはつまりこのインターフェイスでは generic 型を
can have a generic type
持てるということです
The function we have in IDamageable,
IDamageable 内の関数
Damage, takes a parameter of type T.
Damage はパラメーターとして型 T を取ります
When an interface with a generic type is
クラスにより generic 型を持つ
implemented by a class
インターフェイスが実装されている場合は
the type must be chosen.
型を選択する必要があります
Then the corresponding type must be used throughout.
そしてそこで選択された型は使用され続けねばなりません
Implementing an interface comes with some
インターフェイスの実装には
requirements and some benefits.
いくつかの要件とそれに伴う利点が存在します
In order to implement an interface a class must
まずインターフェイスを実装するにはクラスが
publicly declare all of the methods,
インターフェイスに存在する
properties, events and indexers
すべてのメソッド・プロパティ・イベント・インデクサーを
that exist in that interface.
public に宣言する必要があります
Failure to do so will result in an error.
これが行われていない場合はエラーが返されます
The major advantage of interfaces is
インターフェイスの主な利点は
that they allow you to define common functionality
複数のクラス間で一般的な機能を
across many classes, therefore,
定義できる点にあります
you are able to safely make assumptions
このため実装されるインターフェイスから
about what classes can do based on
各クラスで行えることを
the interfaces that they implement.
比較的確実に推測できるわけです
To implement an interface simply add a
インターフェイスを実装するにはクラスの持つ
comma after any inheritance the class has
継承の後ろにカンマを付けて
followed by the name of the interface.
その後ろにインターフェイス名を入力します
If the class doesn't inherit then the comma
クラスが継承を持たない場合は
is not required.
カンマは不要です
If the interface has a generic type
インターフェイスが generic 型を持つ場合は
then the name should be followed by angle brackets
名前が 山カッコで囲まれて
with the type in them.
型とともに入力されます
In this case we have class Avatar,
さて今から見ていくケースではクラス Avatar があり
which inherits from monobehaviour
これは MonoBehaviour を継承します
and implements IKillable and IDamageable
そして IKillable と IDamageable を実装し
with the type Float.
型は Float とします
We must also declare both of the functions
そしてインターフェイスで求められる両方の
required for these interfaces.
関数を宣言する必要があります
Note that the body of the functions is
ここで関数の本文部分は
independent of the interfaces and can be
インターフェイスとは独立しているので
implemented however you would like.
好きなように実装することができます
These sorts of interfaces might be useful
この種のインターフェイスはたとえば製作中のゲームで
if there was a situation in your game where you
一気にダメージを与えたり
wanted to do damage or kill everything.
まとめて殺したりする場合に便利に扱えます
Simply by finding everything that implemented
ただ実装された内容を見ていき
IKillable or IDamageable
この場合は IKillable と IDamageable を
you could be sure that they will have the
見ていけば ダメージやキルの中身も
kill or damage functions.
すぐに見て取れるでしょう
You may be wondering to yourself why you would
ではなぜクラスにインターフェイスを
implement an interface in a class when you could
実装するのでしょう?
just define a function once in a class
関数をクラスの中に書いてそれを
and have other classes inherit from it.
他のクラスでは継承すればいいのでは?
The easy answer is that you can implement
これに対する簡潔な答えは
multiple interfaces, but you cannot inherit
複数のインターフェイスを実装することはできても
from multiple classes, therefore,
複数のクラスを継承することはできないということです
interfaces are a nice way to provide a wide
このため広範にわたる機能を提供するときに
range of functionality.
インターフェイスを使うわけです
The better answer though is that interfaces are
もう少しきちんとした回答をすると インターフェイスは
used to define common functionality across
無関係なさまざまなクラスで
many classes that are unrelated to each other.
共通の機能を使えるよう定義されます
Consider two classes, Wall and Car.
Wall と Car というクラスがあったとしましょう
Wall and Car have very little in common with
当然 Wall と Car にはほとんど共通点がありません
each other except that they both are damageable.
ただしどちらも damageable（破損可能）ではあります
Since they are so different from each other
このように全然中身の違うものに
inheriting from a parent class makes little sense.
親クラスから継承させるのはあまりよい手ではありません
Implementing an interface however works great.
こういった場合にインターフェイスを実装するのは役に立つのです